

COLM ROGERS



Address

Groβe Tulln Straβe 22, 3041 Siegersdorf



& Phone

(0043) 660 9591035



colmrogers91@gmail.com

SOCIAL



LinkedIn

linkedin.com/in/colmrogers/



Website

https://rogers-

1991.github.io/Portfolio Website/

EDUCATION

Higher Diploma in Science with Computing

Griffith College Dublin 1st Class Honours / 2020 - 2021

Certificate, Diploma, 2 Higher Diplomas and 2 Mixing and **Mastering Awards in** Sound Technology in Music/Film

Academy of Sound Dublin Distinctions / 2016-2018

BA Connect in Film Studies with English and Philosophy

NUI Galway 2nd Class Honours / 2010 - 2015

BA in Film Studies

UC Berkeley 3.67/4 GPA / 2014 - 2014

PROFILE

Hardworking & achievement-oriented student recently graduated with a 1st Class Honours Higher Diploma in Science in Computing. Honours graduate of Film Studies with Arts from NUI Galway. Strong technical aptitude, with a 2:1 Honours standard in English and writing, organisation and communication skills and a sincere passion for learning more.

Direct project management experience, handling entire post-production process of film projects, through my post-production company, Rogers Sound. Proficient in the use of audio and video software with experience in various departments, both on location and post-production.

WORK HISTORY

Sound Supervisor, Designer and Editor / Video Editor

Freelance - Dublin

10.2016 - 04.2020

- Supervised entire post-production process of a feature film, including audio, visual, VFX and colour.
- Arranged production meetings and supervised projects sent to different production houses.
- Worked in all audio post-production departments, provided video edit, and supervised Colour, VFX and Music.
- Recorded and mixed sound on-location.
- Created and managed a data library of audio/video files for feature projects.
- Transcoded raw video footage to low-resolution proxies for editing.

Contact Administrator and Customer Care Representative

J1 Ireland – Roscommon

01.2018 - 05.2018 / 01.2019 - 05.2019

- Designed and implemented an application monitoring system, which enabled the business to meet its target of completing over 300 outstanding applications, while simultaneously managing new applications helping to reach all project goals on time.
- Secured over 30 US jobs by meeting and negotiating with owner of Bubba Gump Shrimp in Chicago.
- Contacted US Visa Sponsors and applicants daily regarding completed application forms.

SOFTWARE

- Java
- JavaFX
- MySQL
- HTML and CSS
- JavaScript
- PHP
- Avid Pro Tools 10, 11, 12
- Various Audio Plugin Software
- Adobe Premiere Pro
- Davinci Resolve 14, 15

INTERESTS





Cooking

Playing Music





Gaming

Movies

LANGUAGES

English

Native Speaker

German

Beginner (learning)

WORK HISTORY (continued)

Work Experience

Beacon Studios - Dublin

06.2017 - 08.2017

- Provided a Sound Effects mix and final mix on #Navan2030 promo ad for Irish national TV personality, Hector Ó hEochagáin.
- Answered the phone at reception, took down bookings and inquiries.
- Shadowed sessions with clients.

ACHIEVEMENTS

- Owner and Founder of freelance Audio Post-Production Company, Rogers
 Sound
- Voted Class Rep in Computer Science Course in Griffith College
- Designed website: www.rogerssound.com with Adobe XD (Currently offline)
- Produced, wrote, and directed short film, Chemical Lover
- Built own custom PC
- Voted Equipment Manager of NUIG's Rock (Music) Society
- Credited on 2 Feature Films
- Only student from John Huston Film School to be accepted into UC Berkeley
- Gave film audio lectures at Filmbase, Dublin

QUALITIES

- Technical Competency
- Strong Work Ethic
- Strong Problem Solver
- Creativity
- Patience
- Persistence
- Communication
- Flexibility

REFEREES

Matt Rogers

Director/Owner of J1 Ireland

Phone (00353) 86 8488792 Email matt@j1ireland.com

Noel Storey

Owner of Beacon Studios

Phone (00353) 167 62474 Email noel@beaconstudios.net